Fadi Haddad

Phoenix, AZ FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

(562)-547-7954 haddad207@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/haddad207/ https://github.com/haddad207

Highly competent full-stack developer with over 3 years of professional experience. Driven by the thrill for knowledge, complex problem solving and an enthusiastic mindset. With a proficient ability in translating business requirements into software solutions. Constantly enhancing my area of expertise with online courses. Reliable and responsible team player, dedicated for personal and team growth.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dec 2021 - Jul 2023 **DirecTV** Platform Engineer (DevOps) Los Angeles, CA

- Administrated an instance of Jenkins. Managed application deployment by collaborating with other departments. Achieved AWS Cloud Practitioner Certification.
- Achieved an award for outstanding performance: Solely refactored old Java applications to integrate routine security scanning.
- Visualized security reports via AWS QuickSight, AWS Athena, AWS ETL, AWS DynamoDB, AWS EventBridge and AWS SNS.
- Reducing company costs, implemented a serverless cloud based solution for automated application deployment. Developed using Python, Ansible Tower, VMware, AWS Step Functions, AWS Lambda, AWS API Gateway, AWS S3 Buckets, and Jenkins. Projected yearly company cost reduction of \$494,000.

Oct 2020 - May 2021 **InCube** Software Developer Amman, Jordan

- Developed a proof of delivery application using Flutter (frontend mobile) and .NET (backend). Contains 3 different views: Customer, Driver and Supplier (Warehouse). Functionalities: Sign/Photo on delivery, Driver ETA (with the ability for the driver to change order of delivery with live updates to the customer), Driver tracking, warehouse management, and HEREmaps.
- Developed a dynamic survey module using Flutter, which can be integrated into any existing application.
- Multiple coursework: Microservices, Docker/Kubernetes, C# (SignalR and MVC), Flutter, and Angular.
- Set up a framework for future employers. Trained a team of three developers to a proficient level in Flutter.

ONLINE COURSES (UDEMY.COM)

The Complete Node.js Developer Course (3rd Edition)

- Read/Write data on files, File Upload and Sending Emails.
- REST APIs: how to create API endpoints, Sorting, Pagination and Filtering Data.
- Authentication: Managing Json Web Tokens (JWT).
- Node.js Testing and Debugging.
- · Connecting to a Database: MongoDB, Mongoose via Asynchronous Tasks.
- Socket.io: Real-Time Web Applications (messaging, live updates and more).

React, NodeJS, Express & MongoDB - The MERN Fullstack Guide

- Creating a application for sharing places (Images and location).
- How to manage CRUD (Create, Read, Update and Delete) operations.
- How to handle CORS and Authentication.
- How to manage Database connections for MongoDB and using Mongoose.
- How to use secrets: environment variables such as dotenv.
- Application Deployment: How to Deploy application on Heroku.

React - The Complete Guide:

- · Event Handling/Data Binding. Passing the State up and down.
- React Hooks: useEffect, useState, and custom hooks.
- React Refs & Portals: Creating Modals via React Portal.
- Styling: Vanilla CSS, styled components, and tailwind CSS.
- Debugging React Apps: Breakpoints and React DevTools.
- Data Management: React Context API: useReducer, React-Redux.
- Authentication and API calls: Json Web Token (JTW), and Axios.
- React optimization: useCallback, useMemo and MillionJS.
- Animation: Framer Motion and CSS.

Learn to build an e-commerce store with .Net, React & Redux:

- REST APIs:API endpoints, Swagger, and CRUD operations.
- MVC: Model-View-Controller design.
- .NET Data Management: Pagination, Sorting and Filtering.
- Identity Framework: role management, and JWT Tokens.
- Entity Framework: how to manage data and database connections.
- Hiding data using object DTOS.
- · How to use Stripe for payment management.

Other Courses: Microservices with Node.js and React, UI/UX, DevOps, Deep Learning A-Z 2024: Neural Networks, AI & ChatGPT Prize. Artificial Intelligence A-Z 2024: Build 7 AI + LLM & ChatGPT, and Unreal Engine 5 C++ Developer: Learn C++ & Make Video Games.

SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks: C#, JavaScript, Python, TypeScript, Java, C++, HTML, CSS, .NET, Node.js, Django, Express.js, React.js, Redux, Flutter, Dart, Kotlin, Bootstrap, and Material UI.

Databases & Request handling: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, mySQL, AWS DynamoDB, MSSQL, API, RESTful API and JSON.

Tools & Platforms: AWS, Microservices, Linux, Ansible Tower, AI, Swagger, Jenkins, Azure, Docker, Kubernetes, Git, Jira, Confluence.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in Computer Science:

2015-2020

Honors Graduate with a 3,449 GPA